Finding Aid for Psychiatric-Mental Health Nursing Area (University of Michigan) records, 1973-1982
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Psychiatric-Mental Health Nursing Area (University of Michigan) records 1973-1982
University of Michigan. Psychiatric-Mental Health Nursing Area.
1 linear foot
87271 Bimu C266 2
Records, 1973-1982, of the Psychiatric-Mental Health Nursing area in the University of Michigan School of Nursing. Include course materials and a small amount of miscellaneous materials.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The material was received in 1986 through the Psychiatric-Mental Health Nursing Area office (Donor No. 7342 ).
The record group is open without restriction.
In the fall of 1961 the School of Nursing established a pioneering master's degree program in the area of psychiatric nursing. This program seems to have been the nucleus around which a group of interested faculty gathered, establishing an informal subject area. While its organization remained informal, by the mid-1960's formal responsibility for study in the area was vested in a designated faculty member, who for practical purposes also served as the chair of the Psychiatric Nursing area. This organizational structure continued for several years.
The records of the Psychiatric-Mental Health Nursing Area date from 1973 to 1982 and measure one linear foot in volume. They consist almost exclusively of course material, arranged by course number. In addition, there are a few folders of miscellaneous material.
Subjects:
University of Michigan. School of Nursing.; University of Michigan. Psychiatric-Mental Health Nursing Area.
- Course Material
  - N226, 1976-1977 (Box 1)
  - N235, 1976-1977, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - N268, 1981-1982 (Box 1)
  - N375, 1974-1975, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - N431, 1976-1977 (Box 1)
  - IA52, 1976-1977 (Box 1)
  - N500, 1973-1977 (Box 1)
  - N501, 1973 (Box 1)
  - N502, 1975-1980 (Box 1)
  - N506, 1973-1980 (Box 1)
  - N508, 1973-1976 (Box 1)
  - N510, 1977 (Box 1)
  - N515, 1974-1980 (Box 1)
  - N519, 1979 (Box 1)
  - N521, 1974-1975 (Box 1)
  - N60l, 1973-1981 (Box 1)
  - N602, 1978 (Box 1)
  - N603, 1975-1979 (Box 1)
  - N606, 1974-1979 (Box 1)
  - N608, 1976 (Box 1)
  - N609, 1974-1979 (Box 1)
  - N612, 1980 (Box 1)
  - N670, 1973-1976 (Box 1)
  - N671, 1977-1981 (Box 1)
  - N672, 1978-1981 (Box 1)
  - N673, 1975 (Box 1)
  - N681, 1975-1979 (Box 1)
  - N701, 1981 (Box 1)
  - N727, 1979 (Box 1)
  - N887, 1980-1981 (Box 1)
- Miscellaneous Records
  - Predicting Success in Graduate Programs, 1975 (Box 1)
  - Research, 1976 (Box 1)
  - Senior Level Core Material, 1975-1976 (Box 1)